kanetix.ca 2014-10-07

# The Kanetix.ca Privacy Policy

Your privacy and security

**Our privacy pledge**

Effective on March 14, 2014 

Kanetix Ltd ("KANETIX")® believes in protecting the personal information that you provide us at www.kanetix.ca. We have made safe computing and the protection of your privacy an important priority. KANETIX provides insurance quotes/estimates with minimal personal information. Except where mandated by the government and its regulatory bodies or the courts, the personal information that you share with us will not be shared with third parties without your prior consent. 

Kanetix Ltd has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us here at [contact KANETIX](https://www.kanetix.ca/about_generic_about_history). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site. 

**Security**   
Entering personal data on KANETIX is not only easy but also safe. KANETIX uses an Apache server with SSL (Secure Socket Layer) protocol, among the best Internet security software in the world, and Entrust.net certificates for securing the exchange of confidential data. This security technology encrypts the personal information that you send us (including things like names, addresses, emails and telephone numbers), so it cannot be read by anyone as it travels over the Internet. We will evaluate and adopt new security technology as it becomes available. 

You can find out when the secure SSL connection is activated by looking for the key or padlock icon in the lower corner of your browser window. If the key becomes whole, or the padlock becomes closed, this indicates that the browser is now in "secure" mode. 

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

If you have any questions about security on our website, you can [send us an email through our online form](https://www.kanetix.ca/about_generic_about_history). 

**Cookies**   
Cookies are small pieces of information stored on your hard drive. The only personal information that a cookie can contain is information supplied by the visitor and the cookies we use cannot read data off of our visitor's hard disk or read cookie files created by other websites. 

Cookie technology can save you time by eliminating the need to re-enter frequently requested information. Cookies also give us capability to understand how visitors use our site. We use this information to optimize our website and improve the visitor experience. 

We use both session ID and persistent cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. If you choose to tick the box indicating you would like to be remembered, a persistent cookie is set so you don't have to reenter your login information more than once. If you later decide that you would no longer like to be 'remembered', the cookie will be removed when you log off. You can also remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser's "help" file. 

**Log files**   
As is true of most Web sites, we and our third party tracking-utility partner to gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. 

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. 

**Advertising**   
We partner with a third party ad network to manage our advertising on other sites as well as within our site. Our ad network partner uses cookies to collect non-personal information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests and your actions on our site. We do not have access or control over these cookies. If you wish to not have this information used to serve you targeted ads, you may opt-out of being served targeted ads by [clicking here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads. Please note that you have the option to set your browser to decline our cookies. If you choose not to receive cookies from KANETIX, you may not be able to use all the services available on the site. These cookies are not tied to your personal information. 

**Collecting information**   
We gather and store data about online usage on a collective rather than individual basis. For example, like most websites, we gather aggregate information about the number of visitors that visit our website and the pages that they view, NOT what pages were viewed by each individual. We use this information to anticipate bottlenecks, to gauge the capacity of our servers, and to improve the overall management of our website. 

We also use Commission Junction to track visitors coming from our affiliate sites. This pixel tracking information helps determine the payments we are obliged to make to our affiliates for the traffic they send to us. We also use a third party tracking-utility company which uses pixel tracking to help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. 

Please note that our online usage and affiliate tracking systems do not gather or store personal information. 

**Collecting personal identifiable information**   
In some provinces, KANETIX offers visitors the option of personalized quotes and gathers personal information as part of this process. Depending on the province, this may include obtaining your credit score from a credit reporting agency, or require you to provide details regarding your credit history. This information, along with the other details you enter will be used to provide you with a personalized offer and to determine the payment options that will be available to you. 

Also, from time to time, KANETIX requests and collects personal information from visitors via surveys, contests, "Tell-a-friend" and Renewal Reminder services. Participation is completely voluntary (opt-in). Information requested has included your email address and that of the friend you are referring. 

Finally, you can log in to our site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network. 

**Communication of personal Information**   
At various points on the KANETIX website and when visitors contact KANETIX, visitors may be asked if they consent to sharing their personal information with our affiliates and / or 3rd parties. If they agree, KANETIX provides one or more affiliates and / or 3rd parties with their personal information for the purposes of either preparing or validating an insurance quote or providing marketing services as explicitly requested by the visitor. 

**Email**   
KANETIX will not accept transactions or instructions by Internet email messages. However, questions of a general nature or inquiries may be communicated by [submitting your question online](https://www.kanetix.ca/about_generic_about_history). 

By submitting your question, comment or suggestion online the information you provide becomes the property of KANETIX. Where necessary, we may share the information you provide in your email with 3rd parties in order to address your question, comments or concerns. The content of your email may be used for any purpose and KANETIX is free to use any idea contained in it for any purpose whatsoever, including, but not limited to, developing, manufacturing and marketing products using such information. 

**Tell-a-friend**   
If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Kanetix Ltd. does not store this information. 

**What is this personal information used for?**   
Our surveys are used to identify consumer or improve visitor satisfaction with our site. The 'Tell-a-friend' service sends an email to a friend informing him/her about our site. With our Renewal Reminder service, visitors can elect to have an email reminder sent to them a month before their insurance policy expires. 

We will use the email address you provide us to send you copies of the quotes you have requested to obtain a copy for your records. 

**Policy holder information**   
If you apply online for coverage or purchase a policy online through KANETIX, additional information is needed to process your request. This information may include your first and last name, email address, and dwelling address; your telephone number, driver's licence number, vehicle identification number (if purchasing auto insurance), your current insurance company, employer name and credit card number or bank account information. We may also need to obtain your credit score from a credit reporting agency, or require you to provide details regarding your credit history. This information, along with the other details you have provided will only be used to fulfill services you specifically request. They will not be used for any other reason. 

We forward this information to the insurance company who will be reviewing your application or underwriting your policy. If you agree to purchase a policy from the insurance company, it may use your personal information for the purpose of fulfilling the requested insurance transaction and for future contact in accordance with the terms and conditions of its own privacy policy. 

**Framing**   
Some of our content is served on other pages using framing techniques to serve and provide our content and services on our partner's sites while preserving the look and feel of their site. Please be aware that you are providing your personal information to KANETIX for the services you are requesting and the use of your personal information is governed by this privacy policy. 

Our select partners may also offer you the opportunity to opt-in to receiving information regarding their products and services. If you choose to receive these communications the information you provide is governed by their privacy policy. 

**Service providers**   
In some cases, we use third parties to provide the online quotes you receive on our site or to assist us in advertising our services to you. With respect to the quotes you get, the only information shared with the third party is the information required to provide you with an accurate quote. Depending on the type of quote you are seeking, this information may be comprised of one or more of the following: your age, gender, marital status, smoking status, driving, and insurance history. This information is only shared as necessary for the third party to provide you with an accurate quote. 

These third parties are prohibited from using your personal information for any other purpose. 

**Testimonials**   
We post customer testimonials on our web site which may contain personal information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. If you want your testimonial removed please [contact us through our online form](https://www.kanetix.ca/about_generic_about_history). 

**How can you change your personal information?**   
You can change your username (email address) and password online in the 'My KANETIX' section of the site or you can update your personal information by calling us at 1 (888) 854-2503 or writing to us at [360 Adelaide Street West, Suite 100, Toronto, Ontario, M5V 1R7](https://plus.google.com/107465114783210030737/about?gl=CA&hl=en-CA). 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel, delete or remove your account, or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services [contact us through our online form](https://www.kanetix.ca/about_generic_about_history). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

**For your protection**   
Your password is your private, secret entry code to your account information at KANETIX. It is required when you first log in to view or to modify your saved information. Your password keeps your account information private and secure and you can change it as many times as you like. 

KANETIX contains links to other websites. For example, you may find links to the suppliers featured in our comparison service or links to our affiliated brokerages. We do not exchange any information with these third-party sites if you click on them. If you do decide to click on one of these links, we encourage you to read the privacy statements of these linked sites as their policies may differ from ours. 

**Opting out**   
We provide you the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having your personal information used for certain purposes. For example, in some provinces we may ask your permission to obtain your credit score from a credit reporting agency, or ask you to provide details regarding your credit history. This information, along with the other details you enter will be used to provide you with a personalized offer and to determine the payment options that will be available to you. You can opt to not provide us with this permission and still get quotes. 

Another example in how you can opt out involves our newsletter or renewal reminder service. If you sign up for these optional services we automatically send you a confirmation email specifying the services you requested. From these confirmation emails, you can opt-out of both of these services at any time by replying and indicating your preference to be removed from our lists. You can also opt-out by emailing us at unsubscribe@kanetix.ca, following the unsubscribe instructions in the email communications you receive, calling us at 1 (888) 854-2503 or by writing to us at 360 Adelaide Street West, Suite 100, Toronto, Ontario, M5V 1R7. 

You will be notified when your personal information is collected by any third party that is not our one of our service providers, so you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party. 

**Public Forums**   
Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us through our [online form](https://www.kanetix.ca/about_generic_about_history). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. 

**Social Media Features and Widgets**   
Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

**Single Sign-On**   
You can log in to our site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network. 

**Supplementation of personal information**   
We may obtain information about you from third parties when you provide us with your driver's licence such as name and date of birth. We use this information in order to make it easier for you to use our site and services. 

**Notification of changes**   
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email or by means of a notice on our homepage prior to the change becoming effective. 

**Legal disclaimer**   
We reserve the right to disclose your personal information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our website. 

In the event KANETIX goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personal information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information. 

**If you have any concerns**   
We are committed to providing excellent service to you. However, if you have a concern or complaint, please contact us, because we are also committed to working with you to achieve a resolution and following through to a successful conclusion as quickly as possible. In most cases, complaints are resolved simply by discussing it with us. You should be able to get swift results by:

  * calling one of our customer associates at 1 (888) 854-2503
  * [sending us a question through our online form](https://www.kanetix.ca/about_generic_about_history) or,
  * writing to us at: 

KANETIX  
360 Adelaide Street West, Suite 100  
Toronto ON M5V 1R7
